He goes, as you spoke,
okay, so you go, you call first.
All right.
Brother Calmer.
What does Brother Calmer do?
All right.
You call first?
Are you going to have one?
Right.
Then and there, or do you want to like perhaps?
Okay, so there are, he shows you the three, the three of the fruits that are drugged and says, just a bite.
No, not no, not right now.
All right.
So you now have also take three drugged fruits.
Drug.
Okay.
And there's also the desk to check out, I presume.
I'm just going to look at the desk.
The desk?
I will look at the desk.
All right.
You find a spell scroll of resist poison.
We just put those here.
Find.
I do have to go put these in here.
All right.
You find a spell scroll of resist poison, spell scroll of true seeing, and a spell scroll of resist energy fire.
I'll put those in the party.
I need to put all of these in this party thing.
So let me take care of that later.
All right.
You all?
Okay.
So there's a door to resistance spells.
The spell scroll of true seeing is a spell scroll that allows you to see anything, traps, et cetera, the true nature of creatures.
Can anyone learn it?
It's not, you can't learn it.
It's a scroll, so you can only cast it once.
Oh.
Okay.
So it's not a wizard spell.
It's a scroll.
Anyone can cast it, but you can't.
You have to be, you can't, you're not a wizard, so you can't learn it.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
You are not a wizard.
Alrighty.
You're not a wizard, Harry.
Okay.
And so there's a door to the south.
Belsornig, what's his name?
Brother Eelrich says, it's my bedroom.
Do you must you really plunder my bedroom?
Yes.
All right.
Calmer looks at him and says, Brother Eelrich, I am the head of the clout, your temple was defeated by the Earth Elemental.
Would you have shown me any more dignity?
No, Brother Alrrem.
I'll sit.
Calmer looks at him.
No, Lord Master Calmer.
Better.
All right.
It is time you learned that the oblivion edge does not.
What?
Nothing.
Yes.
Yeah.
All right.
Who goes into the chamber?
Zephyr, Sequioa?
Yeah.
You guys are.
You guys are the rogues.
All righty.
Okay.
The south door opens into another green covered room, 10 feet wide and 30 feet long.
It holds the
right description.
I keep track of all the geysers.
It's tricky.
Oh, the south door opens into a 10-foot-wide, 30-foot-long room.
It contains a pair of beds separated by a folding screen.
By each bed is a small stand, a bronze razier, and a low stool and a lock chest.
Okay.
So who wants to go check out the chests?
More loot.
Calmer.
Let's go.
Calmer goes.
Calmer says, I am not the rogue.
You are the rogue.
You're the leader.
Yeah.
Okay.
He has like the techniques.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, let me go do a slight of hand check on it.
Right?
All right.
Do you
all righty?
All righty.
Okay.
So, okay.
The first chest holds clothing.
Each chest holds clothing, four texts on the elemental evil of water.
So there's ritual books.
Calmer says, I will be taking these.
But brother Eelrich, Brother Eelrich starts whining about, you know, how he deserves these, and these are really religious materials and blah, blah, blah.
And then he again reminds him that he's in charge, right?
So the texts are worth 250 gold pieces each.
We're selling the text.
Are you taking the text or are you leaving the text?
Are these texts important to you?
Yes.
Okay, we'll leave you one.
All right.
So three texts times 200.
So remember, so you guys should have added what is it?
500 gold pieces plus 465 63 563 gold pieces for the treasure you found so far.
Yeah.
That's including the 400 at the beginning.
Yeah, no, that was that's it.
That's total so far.
I'm gonna wait for the total before I add stuff.
Okay, okay.
Dude, we're getting rich.
We're gonna need to go buy some stuff.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, you guys have you like this is the two spoils.
What?
Are you like them?
Oh, sorry.
You became the big bosses.
So the victors go the spoils.
You're the bosses now, man.
Like, that's what happens.
All right.
You find a ceremonial bronze mace.
Let me just put this here.
And a gold ring with a pearl.
And two potions of water breathing.
The same.
Yeah.
And the chests that Sequioa opened.
If you take the potion of water breathing and you fight the elemental water thingy.
It's not water.
Water.
The water breathing not just gives you air.
What did you say, Nick?
I was hoping the water breathing just gave you air.
No, the thing is not water.
It's a water elemental.
It's a kind of an elemental intelligence.
Does that make sense?
Oh, the water itself is?
Yes, the water itself is living.
Well, that's scary.
Yes.
So, yes.
In fact, when you go through the books, you realize you start to wonder how much Brother Eelrich knew about this creature
and whether he's somebody you should be trusting going forward.
Probably not.
Well, maybe you can't trust him, but we need everything else.
All right.
We want to make it known that you know his game and that he's on a very tight leash.
Maybe threaten his life a little bit more.
Yep.
So, you know, you're not the big boss anymore, so no more surprises in these rooms, okay?
Brother Eelrich.
Yes, of course, of course, of course, of course.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
The next surprise will be meant for you, okay?
Roll intimidation.
Who has a good intimidation?
I have like minus one.
I got a minus one.
Can someone help me?
Yeah, I gotcha.
Calmer helps you.
I rolled badly both times.
Who did you roll?
Nine.
Brother Eelrich acknowledges you.
All right.
All righty.
Okay.
And with that, boys and girls, do you want to head back to your lair and rest because you're down lots of hit points?
All right.
And now, since you defeated and plundered the water temple, you are level nine.
Level nine.
What are you?
Level eight right now, right?
Yeah, we're level eight right now.
Yeah.
All right, so you should be level nine.
Let's see what we gain at level 10.
So, how much gold did we gain in total?
Let me see.
So, you gains.
Hold on, I forgot that I didn't cut and paste the other trainer.
Logical ambush.
If you have the invisible condition when you cast a spell on that creature,
master chemically.
All right, so that's 2,400.
Okay.
This each.
Hold on, hold on.
That was how much you found.
Let me find, let me do the math.
Give me a second.
Two,
three times 250 plus 87.
828.
And don't forget, you have to subtract 10% for.
Oh, yeah, there's attack.
I forgot.
So
745.
Okay.
Don't forget.
Dream expects to get paid.
So I just took the tax off, right?
All right.
And so now we have enough time for you guys to raise a level.
I just did that.
You did it?
I only got one.
No, if I'm invisible, I can give stuff this advantage.
And I assume if something has disadvantage, I get a sneak attack, right?
Yes, if you're hidden.
No, no, no.
It's very weird.
It's invisible and I cast a spell, it gets disadvantage.
I can walk on water.
Oh, you can walk on water now?
How convenient?
All right.
Nick, don't forget to check.
Don't forget to check your spells.
Also, because I got really annoyed, I made it easy.
If you want to, I made it very easy to look at RPGbot.
Oh, no, I don't need any.
You don't get any spells?
Okay.
No.
I have toll the dead, which is also something I can use.
Me too.
By the way, if you go to this directory, if you go here, I created simpler eight web pages for looking at RPGbot because I couldn't deal with his crap.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Sorry, they're not everywhere.
So I have it for the rogue.
I didn't do it for the monk.
I'm sorry.
I should do it for the monk as well, but I did it for the rogues.
Sorry that not every computer scientist is a major.
Not every DD players computer science major.
Okay, so let's see what does he do?
Calmer goes to ninth level.
I don't get anything.
I just get spells.
Okay.
Everybody's level nine.
Any actions?
All right.
Calmer needs to get a spell now, right?
Oh, shit.
Let me do this.
You guys probably want Calmer to have good spells, right?
All right.
Do we want to get commune so I can ask a god a question?
Greater restoration to restore us from any horrible.
Wait, hold on, there's more.
Scrying so I could spy or summon Celestial so we could have one more ally.
I think scrying would be nice.
Well, so, yeah.
If you want to spy on like the other bosses,
buying, you scrying?
Ask the gods could be also good.
It's really temple of elemental.
Okay, scry or greater restoration.
All right.
Okay.
So I think he'll get greater restoration for the moment if we're going to go because that summon celestial greater restoration.
Some celestial data restoration.
Summon celestial.
He's made up his mind.
What do you take?
He took greater restoration.
Sure, is that it?
Can I have one more spell?
How many fourth level spells do I have?
Let's see what does I recommend.
The guy recommends for fourth level.
Ah, that's a word.
I already have that one.
Third level.
We didn't even know the spell existed.
Astral flood.
What is it I can learn?
Nothing.
It's not a spell I can learn.
Oh.
Hold on.
It's kind of like a fireball for clerics.
Cleric, that a fireball?
No.
Here, let me show you what it does.
That's interesting.
What?
This is a new
fireballs?
No, no, I just to give you an idea of what the spell does, right?
Why didn't I use this spell before?
Fulmer read about this spell.
All right.
Okay.
Take a long rest, everyone.
And let's go to the first level because that's where your layer is.
Guys, now I can now mimic another person's speech or handwriting.
Oh, nice.
Let's go.
All right.
Ah, there you go.
So you're sitting in your chambers, right?
And then Dren knocks on the door.
Morning, Dren.
How's it going?
Hello.
Holy.
Boss, there's a man outside.
Says Barkinar sent him to see the household.
Soft looking, gray, smiles too much.
I had Kriel pat him down.
He laughed about it and let us.
I don't trust him, but he does look harmless.
Do you let him in?
Yeah, sure.
All right.
He goes, forgive me the intrusion.
And if it's okay, may I brought some wine.
I'm Alrrem.
Well, Lucius Alrrem, when I'm working.
It's a long story and a dull one.
Barkinar, just to remind you, Barkinar is the guy who you met after you won the war.
Remember that?
Right.
Well, I'm working.
It's a long story and a dull one.
Barkinar asked me to make sure the new management has everything it needs.
And between us, I think he undersold the job four profits in a day.
The man could barely say it without smiling.
And he never smiles.
Sit it.
I brought you something to take the edge off.
And then you're going to tell me what you're sort of.
And I'm going to fix it.
That's the whole of my talent.
I carry things from clever people to clever people.
And you four are the cleverest thing to happen here in a year.
What's the last cleverest thing?
What?
Well, the last cleverest thing.
What happened a year ago?
Yeah, that's what I want to know.
That's a question for Barkinar.
Okay.
With Barkinar again?
Remember when you remember when you guys defeated all the forces when you won the war?
Yep.
Right?
There was a guy who showed up and said, I had four problems in the morning and they're all gone.
Yeah, yeah.
That's Barkinar.
He's the guy.
Yes, he's the boss.
He's the guy between you and the next layer of management.
He also warned you about Hartsch.
He's the next guy.
He also warned you about.
Yes.
He was also Hartsch's.
He was the guy who was the head of the Earth Temple before Hartsch got the, before he got promoted.
So he's kind of an interesting character between you and whoever's above him.
All right.
So he says, but
he goes, and I think that I think he then says, first of all, let me bring you this cask of excellent good wine.
He clicks his fingers.
Dren, can you bring that cask you told me to keep outside?
Boss, do you want me to bring the cask?
I've heard of these casks exploding.
Bring it in.
Dren turns to Zephyr and says, dude, I was talking to the boss.
You and I are peers.
Calmer says, all right, keep telling yourself that.
Calmer turns to Zephyr, turns to Dren and says, my dear Dren, I am more concerned with the spiritual matters of the earth, the earth temple gods.
I don't concern myself with these petty operational details.
Please consult my ally.
Please talk to Sequioa, Zephyr, and Zinnia for these things.
Zinnia will be in charge of all intelligence operations.
Well, I'm clearly the most dominant guy here.
So I will.
Zephyr will be my chief operating officer for all things related to how we need to run the system.
And Sequioa will be in charge of, well, making sure that things get into my hands and not out of my hands.
Got it.
You've heard Calmer.
Now, quick get to my task.
Cask, whatever.
All right.
So Calmer sits down and starts reading, goes back to reading whatever he was reading.
Okay.
So you have a cask of genuinely good wine.
He also says, for the household.
And he provides you a potion of superior healing.
Are you trying to pour some wine for pour some wine for Lucius?
Okay.
Then he says, and here is a potion of superior healing.
Each for the household.
So you all now have a potion of superior healing.
So add that to yourself.
Each of us?
Okay.
Yeah.
I mean, guys, you're the heads of an evil temple, and he's your supply chain.
That's true.
I mean, you do realize evil, right?
I mean, that's you're the big bosses, right?
Yep.
There are advantages to being the big bosses.
Don't forget to take a long rest, guys.
Not that I'm expecting combat, but
84.
Okay.
Okay, and now hold on.
I'm not done.
So what's the total amount of gold I was supposed to add from the 583?
745.
700.
Oh wow.
Being the head of an evil cult does have its benefits.
I forgot.
Why is Lucius giving us all this?
Because we're the big ahead.
Well, you can ask.
So you can ask him.
Lucius, what do we owe all this loot?
He goes, perhaps Barkinar didn't explain my role.
No.
I see.
My job is to make sure that what the temple needs, the temple gets.
I am sort of, I am the conduit from Nulb to the temple.
And one of my special privileges is to work with the leadership of the temple.
And in this case, that would be you to get them whatever little thing they might need or want.
Thank you.
So, might I ask if you could bring us to the Nulb so we could purchase some magical items?
But that's beneath you.
I can procure these things and let me make sure you know what I can procure.
Oh, yeah, wait, we can get magic items without spending money right now.
No, no.
You spend money.
Money still has to be spent.
Yeah.
But you don't have to go to Nulb.
He acts as your middleman.
Well, Calmer, any dagger, magical dagger, I'd be most welcome.
All right, so hold on.
Let me just.
Oh, yeah.
A magical dagger and a magical short sword would be really nice.
All right.
So let me just.
Right.
Okay.
So,
okay.
So he says,
so he says,
okay, so he says, well, what is it that you need?
Do you need something for survivability?
Mobility and infiltration?
Something to quickly run away?
Something to fight a caster?
Or some specific item that it will take me just a few days to collect.
Just like because I knew that, hold on.
Because I knew that you might need something right now on the right now on lead time.
Let me just show you what I have.
He's
a good idea.
Dren turns to Zephyr.
Oh, sorry.
Is my audio working now?
Yep.
Right.
So Dren turns to Zephyr.
Boss, last time I checked, there's these chests that turn into mimics.
Do you want me to bring the chest in?
All right.
If it turns into a mimic, I'm just outside.
He brings the chest.
All right.
He goes, well, let me see what we have here.
I have a ring of protection for survivability.
For mobility and infiltration, I have a hat of disguise.
Wait, did you say something invisibility?
No, ring of protection.
Oh, sorry.
I heard invisibility.
For infiltration.
Infiltration, not invisibility.
To sneak inside.
Yeah.
I have, sorry, I have several things.
I have boots of levitation, a hat of disguise, or a ring of feather falling.
How much do they cost?
Do I have to buy them or?
Unfortunately, yes, these are not free.
I'm a middleman, and there are people I must pay.
And the rule, and Lord Hedrak has made it quite clear that although I'm offering these things, I'm not giving them away for free.
The temple does have expenses that need to be paid.
Earth elementals cannot cost that much to maintain.
Like, what's the maintenance cost on an elemental?
He goes, all right, so I put the list there so you guys can see it.
The things.
Anything you guys want?
Let me see.
Whereas this is superior healing.
Just to be clear, the potion of superior healing is what you already got.
So that one was a free gift.
That was a freebie.
Oh, a dagger of venom.
You already have, no, no, just instead of dagger of venom, just if there's a one, there's a plus one, you want a plus one weapon of some kind.
I'll take a plus one weapon.
Could take a short set plus one.
Yeah, I'll also take a short set plus one.
All right, so let me just tell you what the prices for that are.
Okay.
What did you say?
You said that you wanted a sword plus one, right?
Yeah.
All right, that's a thousand gold pieces.
Deal.
All right.
Is there any okay?
Romag, did you also get one?
All right.
He goes, excellent choice.
Excellent choice.
The blood, this was procured from who was it procured from?
Does it really matter?
I hope you use it to strike down the enemies of the temple and raise us all to greater power.
Great.
All right.
Is there anything else you would like?
So let me just say this: if you want to go do some research and come back to me next week, I'll assume that you did that.
All right.
But it won't be given to you today.
It'll show up in the DD list.
Is there a rule to anyway?
Let me just send you something.
If you go to DD Beyond, right?
I'm going to send you a document.
I'm going to point, let me just do this.
I'm going to put a document.
Let me see.
I'm uploading a document.
I'll take a few seconds there.
So it's going to take a few seconds to upload, and it's got, it's going to be called same magical prices.
Just go through there and pick something.
Okay?
These are the things he has right now.
Everything else will take a few to three days.
If there's something that you want,
is there anything else that you guys see there that you might want?
By the way,
things that are there might not be there in a day, so just keep that in mind.
What is it?
You already have one of those.
That's the
look like a monkey.
Yeah, there's not anything useful.
You don't get any armor.
I mean, I guess there's some rings that you could get.
Rings.
Well, so, so, so, for example, for you, things that would help are boots of levitation because it helps in different directions.
Hold on, hold on.
Hold on.
Let him let you.
You can get lots of things.
He's a little bit more restrained.
Rings of protection are also good because they give you better armor class.
How much did the boost cost?
3,500 gold pieces.
Which one?
But a ring of protection.
Ring of protection.
Okay, I'll see what it is.
It's actually a very useful item.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think it also gives you it also gives you other abilities, I think.
And saving through plus one to saving through.
Yeah, that is a big deal.
Okay, I'll get 150.
That's a little powerful.
Yeah.
Ring of protection plus one.
Oh, AT.
I didn't want to realize I added one key saving to us.
Yeah, no, that's why it's powerful.
Let's give it to the monk who can't wear armor, doesn't wear weapons?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The monk should get it.
I was just mentioning that seems very powerful.
No, it is very powerful.
That's why it's 3,500 gold pieces.
Jesus.
Yes, you are correct.
It is very powerful.
Man, you're about to go in debt, dude.
All right.
I'll have to think about what Calmer wants.
Top of my head, I can't think of something.
Zephyr, is there anything that you want from that list or do you want to think about it for a week?
Think about it.
Good for now.
Oh, it says good.
What?
It says pipe.
Or do you see pipe?
Oh, wait, I'm on the wrong thing.
Boots of levitation, hat of disguise, ring of feather falling, motion of speed, bell scroll of teleport.
It's a staff of striking.
The feather falling, is that jump from anyone?
Basically, you can't fall down and get hurt.
I'll wait.
Okay, staff of striking or something we already have.
So I think
striking.
No, not one is 21,000 gold pieces.
He cannot afford it.
What is the staff of striking of 21,000 gold pieces?
A very rare magical item.
What does it do?
Axe is a plus three bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls.
It has 10 charges.
When you hit with a melee attack using it, you can expend up to three charges for each charge you expend.
The target takes an extra 1d6 force damage.
All right.
Oh, oh, hold on.
I missed one.
Sorry, Nick.
I missed two.
These might be of interest to somebody.
I'll take the ring of invisibility.
Ring of invisibility or ring of free action.
How much is the ring of invisibility?
That one's very expensive.
10,000 gold pieces.
Oh, yeah, that's not happening.
What's the ring of free action?
That is also very expensive.
20,000 gold pieces.
Why is that so good?
Free action can't be a paralyzed held like
all difficult terrain appears as normal terrain.
It basically means that any monster that has the ability to affect the terrain or to slow you down can't affect you.
Why did that happen with a free action?
Called ring of free action.
Yeah.
That's why it's called.
It means that you are never the ring of free action is
while you're wearing this ring, difficult terrain doesn't cost you extra movement.
In addition, magic can neither reduce any of your speeds nor cause you to have paralyzed or restrained conditions.
Well, when I get the money, perfect.
All right.
So just so you know what it is.
Calmer, Lucia says,
Zephyr, as much as I would like to promise that this would always be here, I think that if you wish to keep it on the back so that I would sell it, a small deposit of 4,000 gold pieces would be necessary.
I do have other buyers.
4,000 gold pieces?
Yes.
And it's how much in total?
Ring of free action?
There's 20,000.
Okay.
No.
You will not be paying this.
And for you, Sequioa, the ring of invisibility, he offers to keep it away from people for 4,000 gold pieces.
So when you have the rest of the money, you can buy it.
That way, it doesn't go away.
Of course, you may end up killing him or whatever, but I'm just telling you, like, that's where the situation is.
All right.
Well, we good.
Yep.
Thank you.
All right.
Being the evil bosses has its advantages, yes?
Yep.
You must steal more money.
Yeah, there's more money to be all of a sudden.
You become motivated to get more money, right?
Yep.
All right.
See you guys.
Yep.